<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Giuseppe's RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Giuseppe Gangi personal blog]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 15:09:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Life Update - Leaving Germany]]></title><description><![CDATA[Yesterday I made an implementation on my Telegram bot to set a limit of duration to the files to convert, but I am not 100% happy, I would…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/life-update-leaving-germany/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/life-update-leaving-germany/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I made an implementation on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ggangix/Youtube-to-Audio-Telegram-Bot&quot;&gt;Telegram bot&lt;/a&gt; to set a limit of duration to the files to convert, but I am not 100% happy, I would like to implement something to split audio, my first idea is doing it just on special cases and using ffmpeg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For today I started this implementation and I hope to finish it in the nex days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy coding.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[25/100 days of code - Making a solution to split audio on my telegram bot]]></title><description><![CDATA[Yesterday I made an implementation on my Telegram bot to set a limit of duration to the files to convert, but I am not 100% happy, I would…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/twenty-fifth-day/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/twenty-fifth-day/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I made an implementation on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ggangix/Youtube-to-Audio-Telegram-Bot&quot;&gt;Telegram bot&lt;/a&gt; to set a limit of duration to the files to convert, but I am not 100% happy, I would like to implement something to split audio, my first idea is doing it just on special cases and using ffmpeg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For today I started this implementation and I hope to finish it in the nex days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy coding.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[24/100 days of code - get duration of a video without download with youtube-dl]]></title><description><![CDATA[Introduction Yesterday was day-off because I got sick, but today I was ready to keep coding. I noticed that my Telegram bot to Download…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/get-duration-youtube-dl/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/get-duration-youtube-dl/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was day-off because I got sick, but today I was ready to keep coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I noticed that my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ggangix/Youtube-to-Audio-Telegram-Bot&quot;&gt;Telegram bot&lt;/a&gt; to Download youtube files got stucked for a strange reason, after check was because telegram has a limit to bots to don&apos;t send audios greater than 50MB so I had to make a modification in the bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First idea that came to my mind was to add a 3rd party service or self host the audio for some days and send the link to every user, but after thinking along the day, the concept is to keep it simple, so I did something different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As maybe you know by my source code, I am using youtube-dl to download videos and extract audio, so to check the duration first without download the file, I am using the following command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;youtube-dl --simulate --get-duration  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that way I can check the time and compare with the max allowed time before download and send it by using telegram API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy coding.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[23/100 days of code - A day to refactor]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today the inspiration to start a new project wasn't in the top, so I made a little active pause by refactoring a little bit some pieces of…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/twenty-third-a-day-to-refactor/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/twenty-third-a-day-to-refactor/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today the inspiration to start a new project wasn&apos;t in the top, so I made a little active pause by refactoring a little bit some pieces of code in the blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s continue tomorrow with more enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[22/100 days of code - Telegram bot to download and convert youtube video to audio]]></title><description><![CDATA[I finished the first stable version of my Telegram Bot to download youtube videos, convert to audio and send it back, for now it's really…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/telegram-bot-to-download-youtube-audio/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/telegram-bot-to-download-youtube-audio/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I finished the first stable version of my Telegram Bot to download youtube videos, convert to audio and send it back, for now it&apos;s really simple just made the function, but I am quite happy with the result in the short time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the source code here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ggangix/Youtube-to-Audio-Telegram-Bot.git&quot;&gt;https://github.com/ggangix/Youtube-to-Audio-Telegram-Bot.git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install youtube-dl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone the repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;npm install&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add an .env file with the following structure:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;TELEGRAM_TOKEN=
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[21/100 days of code - Creating a Telegram bot to convert Youtube videos]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today I started to code a Telegram bot that use youtube downloader to download and convert youtube videos, for now I only have the bot that…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/starting-a-telegram-bot/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/starting-a-telegram-bot/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today I started to code a Telegram bot that use youtube downloader to download and convert youtube videos, for now I only have the bot that receive messages and in the other side the downloader, I would like to merge both in the next days of coding. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am very pleased to have the possibility to code things that makes me have some fun time.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[20/100 days of code - Add a parameter to Auto Populate Replies twitter]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today I made a couple of changes to the twitter bot that I made yesterday, because I noticed that was no replying to all the mentioned user…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/auto-populate-reply-twitter-bot/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/auto-populate-reply-twitter-bot/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today I made a couple of changes to the twitter bot that I made yesterday, because I noticed that was no replying to all the mentioned user in a tweet. This happen because we have to add the following parameter to the update message: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   auto_populate_reply_metadata: true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think is working better now, I also added a couple of logs more and deployed better on the server. I have more things on mind, let&apos;s see how works.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[19/100 days of code - Create a Twitter Bot that reply random messages]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today I refactored a twitter bot that I made some time ago to basically reply random messages from a list to all the tweets that receive one…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/twitter-reply-bot-random-messages/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/twitter-reply-bot-random-messages/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today I refactored a twitter bot that I made some time ago to basically reply random messages from a list to all the tweets that receive one user account with a certain trigger word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code is really simple and short and you can find it here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ggangix/twitterReplyBot&quot;&gt;https://github.com/ggangix/twitterReplyBot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the bot in action if you tweet &quot;grita&quot; to the @elabominablebot twitter account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instructions to use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone the repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;npm install&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add an .env file with the following structure:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;TWITTER_API_KEY=
TWITTER_API_SECRET_KEY=
TWITTER_ACCESS_TOKEN=
TWITTER_ACCESS_TOKEN_SECRET=
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill the config.json with the information that you want to use to your bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;twitterUserToTrack: The twitter user that you want to listen for an specific word&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;triggerWord: The word that will trigger the reply.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;messages: An array with replies to be selected randomly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;npm start and have fun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[18/100 days of code - Start using my vps]]></title><description><![CDATA[I wanted to use the app I made yesterday to publish the RSS feed to my Twitter account, and how I want to make more scripts like that one…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/eighteenth-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/eighteenth-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to use the app I made yesterday to publish the RSS feed to my Twitter account, and how I want to make more scripts like that one, so I create a droplet on Digital Ocean to do some nice things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently I am using pm2 to manage the application process.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[17/100 days of code - Create an app to tweet from RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today I created and nodejs app to check the RSS Feed that I created yesterday, every certain time (6 hours by default), and tweet in my…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/seventeenth-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/seventeenth-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today I created and nodejs app to check the RSS Feed that I created yesterday, every certain time (6 hours by default), and tweet in my personal account if there is a new blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ggangix/rssFeedToTweet&quot;&gt;https://github.com/ggangix/rssFeedToTweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone the repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;npm install&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add an .env file with the following structure:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;FEED_RSS=
TWITTER_API_KEY=
TWITTER_API_SECRET_KEY=
TWITTER_ACCESS_TOKEN=
TWITTER_ACCESS_TOKEN_SECRET=
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;npm start and have fun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[16/100 days of code - Creating an RSS Feed with Gatsby]]></title><description><![CDATA[I have in mind some ideas to automatize process from the blog to my personal social networks, something like after publish a post, share it…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/sixteenth-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/sixteenth-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 18:41:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I have in mind some ideas to automatize process from the blog to my personal social networks, something like after publish a post, share it on my Twitter and tiny things like that. But of course to do that I needed some kind of structure where I can take the data to my future scripts. So the first option that come to me was to add a RSS Feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install gatsby-plugin-feed
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then in gatsby-config.js you have to define the data that you want to add to the xml file, a good example is this one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;module.exports = {
  plugins: [
    {
      resolve: `gatsby-plugin-feed`,
      options: {
        query: `
          {
            site {
              siteMetadata {
                title
                description
                siteUrl
                site_url: siteUrl
              }
            }
          }
        `,
        feeds: [
          {
            serialize: ({ query: { site, allMarkdownRemark } }) =&gt; {
              return allMarkdownRemark.edges.map(edge =&gt; {
                return Object.assign({}, edge.node.frontmatter, {
                  description: edge.node.excerpt,
                  date: edge.node.frontmatter.date,
                  url: site.siteMetadata.siteUrl + edge.node.fields.slug,
                  guid: site.siteMetadata.siteUrl + edge.node.fields.slug,
                  custom_elements: [{ &quot;content:encoded&quot;: edge.node.html }],
                })
              })
            },
            query: `
              {
                allMarkdownRemark(
                  sort: { order: DESC, fields: [frontmatter___date] },
                ) {
                  edges {
                    node {
                      excerpt
                      html
                      fields { slug }
                      frontmatter {
                        title
                        date
                      }
                    }
                  }
                }
              }
            `,
            output: &quot;/rss.xml&quot;,
            title: &quot;Your Site&apos;s RSS Feed&quot;,
          },
        ],
      },
    },
  ],
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Build and have fun&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now after each Gatsby build the rss.xml will be automatically update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.com/docs/adding-an-rss-feed/&quot;&gt;https://www.gatsbyjs.com/docs/adding-an-rss-feed/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[15/100 days of code - Installing Google Analytics]]></title><description><![CDATA[I was a little bit curious about how easy or not is to integrate google analytics with Gatsby, and as I imagine was easy using the gatsby…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/fifteenth-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/fifteenth-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 17:15:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I was a little bit curious about how easy or not is to integrate google analytics with Gatsby, and as I imagine was easy using the &lt;strong&gt;gatsby-plugin-google-analytics&lt;/strong&gt; just have to add the basic configuration to the gatsby-config.js file and that&apos;s it. It&apos;s working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, I fixed and issue related with the CNAME file, necessary to point to the domain giuseppe.xyz but it had been overwrote after each build, to solve that, I had to create and static directory and put the CNAME file inside, in that way will be in the public directory after build and available in the branch gh-pages.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[14/100 days of code - Fixing some issues]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today the first day after my blog is online, I noticed some visualizations issues when you try to access to the website from a mobile phone…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/fourteenth-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/fourteenth-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 19:53:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today the first day after my blog is online, I noticed some visualizations issues when you try to access to the website from a mobile phone, so I spend the last hour fixing thoses problems, and now looks better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also changed the format of the dates because I would like to show something like &quot;2020-11-26&quot; rather than &quot;2 days ago&quot;, I don&apos;t know, just personal preferences 😉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I would try to do something else tomorrow, and bring the fun to the roof.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[13/100 days of code - We are online!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Finally and after 13 days of the 100 days of code challenge, the blog is online and ready to new adventures. For now I am using gh-pages…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/thirteenth-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/thirteenth-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 19:13:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Finally and after 13 days of the 100 days of code challenge, the blog is online and ready to new adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now I am using gh-pages, but I&apos;m planning to move it to my own server in the near future, for now I&apos;m quite happy with the result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to deploy a gatsby blog using Github pages? (1)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Configure github repo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigate to your site’s repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under the repository name, click Settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the GitHub Pages section, use the Source drop-down to select master (for publishing to the root subdomain) or gh-pages (for publishing to a path like /docs) as your GitHub Pages publishing source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click Save.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installing the gh-pages package&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install gh-pages --save-dev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Add deploy script to package.json&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  &quot;scripts&quot;: {
    &quot;deploy&quot;: &quot;gatsby build --prefix-paths &amp;#x26;&amp;#x26; gh-pages -d public&quot;
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and then: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm run deploy
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your site will be in the configured domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.com/docs/how-gatsby-works-with-github-pages/#configuring-the-github-pages-source-branch&quot;&gt;https://www.gatsbyjs.com/docs/how-gatsby-works-with-github-pages/#configuring-the-github-pages-source-branch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[12/100 days of code - Final steps]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today I made the Privacy Policy page and also wrote down some paragraph more to the about page. I think is enought for now, and I can…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/twelfth-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/twelfth-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 18:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today I made the Privacy Policy page and also wrote down some paragraph more to the about page. I think is enought for now, and I can publish the blog tomorrow on my 13th day of the challenge, It is very special to me because tomorrow it&apos;s Friday and 😱 the 13th! 😱.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sure that I can improve the visualization and the content but this is the point of the challenge to be active and keep doing things day by day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s DO IT!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[11/100 days of code - Creating a timeline component]]></title><description><![CDATA[I finally wrote something to the about page, so I had this Idea to show graphically part of my life, so I think a good start was to make…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/eleventh-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/eleventh-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I finally wrote something to the about page, so I had this Idea to show graphically part of my life, so I think a good start was to make this verticalTimeline component, to start to write down this ideas, I think the website is almost complete, but I want to pulish a bit and launch in the next days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The component was really easy to made using tailwindcss. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[10/100 days of code - Implementing social buttons]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today I took the early shift to make the challenge because I'll be busy in the afternoon. I made a Social Buttons component to link to my…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/tenth-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/tenth-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today I took the early shift to make the challenge because I&apos;ll be busy in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a Social Buttons component to link to my personal networks. Very happy with the result, just left to abstract a little bit the component but for now it&apos;s working fine.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[9/100 days of code - Something is better than nothing]]></title><description><![CDATA[I had not 100% motivation today, but I changed the favicon and also remove the contact page. Not proud about my progress but I'll do it much…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/nineth-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/nineth-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 17:35:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I had not 100% motivation today, but I changed the favicon and also remove the contact page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not proud about my progress but I&apos;ll do it much better tomorrow, without any doubts.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[8/100 days of code - Retouching styles]]></title><description><![CDATA[I did a lot of style modifications to have the project almost done from this area.  I have some things important still to do like write down…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/eighth-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/eighth-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 17:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I did a lot of style modifications to have the project almost done from this area. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have some things important still to do like write down a really nice About page where I want to include &lt;em&gt;all my life&lt;/em&gt;, I will try to have it done before day 15, because I would like to to publish the blog and then work in other projects I have on mind to this challenge.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[7/100 days of code - Images for posts and presentation]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today I added the image field to every post to be use in the Home Page lastest posts component, and also make a brief presentation in the…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/seventh-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/seventh-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 19:40:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today I added the image field to every post to be use in the Home Page lastest posts component, and also make a brief presentation in the same page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to write a large About me page in the nexts days and touch a little bit the design to have my blog complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s keep coding.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[6/100 days of code - Add a card component to show the last post]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today I made a cards component to visualize the last 3 post in the home view, it's not perfect right now but I hope to improve it with the…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/sixth-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/sixth-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 19:40:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today I made a cards component to visualize the last 3 post in the home view, it&apos;s not perfect right now but I hope to improve it with the days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made use of StaticQuery for the first time, and it was nice to have the experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think is the day where I am more tired, so was difficult to be concentrate, let&apos;s see tomorrow that is saturday to make a better progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s keep coding.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[5/100 days of code - Add keywords to every post, using a graphql field]]></title><description><![CDATA[Well on this day after I failed to upgrade to the new tailwind version (2.0) that they release yesterday, I wanted to do something…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/fifth-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/fifth-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Well on this day after I failed to upgrade to the new tailwind version (2.0) that they release yesterday, I wanted to do something productive, so I added a new field to every post, this field is called tags and it will be used for the component SEO to create the meta keywords to every page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I made some personalizations in the colors of the site, still not sure about the palette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s keep coding.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[4/100 days of code - Styling markdown using tailwind]]></title><description><![CDATA[In my continue try to give to the blog section a look and feel like a real blog I worked today on use some tailwind classes to add style to…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/fourth-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/fourth-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In my continue try to give to the blog section a look and feel like a &lt;em&gt;real blog&lt;/em&gt; I worked today on use some tailwind classes to add style to the single post template.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m not 100% convinced of the results but I think is a good start point, I am also thinking on the palette of colors that I want to use, and of course planning to work in the other sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I need to spend more than one hour some day, because I really want to have it done and continue the challenge with other kind of projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s keep coding.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[3/100 days of code - Integrate blog to the layout]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today was the day to integrate a litlle bit the blog list and single post page, to do that I am using the layout and seo components. Easy…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/third-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/third-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today was the day to integrate a litlle bit the blog list and single post page, to do that I am using the layout and seo components. Easy and clean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary of my day:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate blog and blog post using the layout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created single post template.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link every post to the single post page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sort blog post by date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add some style to the list of post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote down this post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s continue learning and having fun with this challenge!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2/100 days of code - Human-readable urls]]></title><description><![CDATA[To start the second day I wanted to have a complete route to access to every post. So, I read a little bit about how to do it and was more…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/second-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/second-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;To start the second day I wanted to have a complete route to access to every post. So, I read a little bit about how to do it and was more easy that I thought. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary of my day:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created dinamically one route for every markdown file. With user friendly urls defined by the filename.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created single post template.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a link to the blog in the header.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed the names of the first two post (not sure yet about it).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrote down this post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For tomorrow I would like to integrate the blog and single post with the rest of the site, and style is still pending.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[1/100 days of code - Creating a blog with Gatsby and Tailwind]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello there, this is my first day of 100 on the challenge to spend at least 1 hour a day to code personal projects. Quick Introduction I am…]]></description><link>https://giuseppe.xyz/first-day-100daysofcode/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://giuseppe.xyz/first-day-100daysofcode/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 17:15:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello there, this is my first day of 100 on the challenge to spend at least 1 hour a day to code personal projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Quick Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a IT Engineer, the last years I&apos;ve been working as a Web Developer (mostly on Javascript), during this time I failed several times in my purpose to spend some time coding in personal projects, learning new things or just have fun with maybe the &quot;thing&quot; I am sure I love to do, PROGRAMMING!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need this time and this challenge to create the habit and come back to my roots, and learn new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Day 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I have been working in my personal blog, I have another one running using Jekkyl (Ruby). But I would like to learn and use Gatsby.js and Tailwind CSS because the last weeks I saw some videos and websites and looks really nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installing Gatsby Tailwind Starter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a Gatbsy+Tailwind starter repository, so I cloned it to be the base of this blog you are reading :D &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gatsby new blog https://github.com/taylorbryant/gatsby-starter-tailwind
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we can run it &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd blog
npm run develop
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that I took a quick look about the structure and use, and create the folder posts/ and wrote down this &lt;strong&gt;colossal&lt;/strong&gt; text to the first post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installing gatsby-source-filesystem and gatsby-transformer-remark&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok we have the first post, but where is the blog? well we need to install &lt;strong&gt;gatsby-source-filesystem&lt;/strong&gt; to be able to take local system data to the Gatsby app and &lt;strong&gt;gatsby-transformer-remark&lt;/strong&gt; to transform markdown files to HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install gatsby-source-filesystem
npm install gatsby-transformer-remark
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I added this to the configuration to source the posts folder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    {
      resolve: `gatsby-source-filesystem`,
      options: {
        name: `posts`,
        path: `${__dirname}/src/posts/`,
      },
    },
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Create a blog page&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a blog page iterating the markdown files in the posts folder, for now without any style or something just for test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Github&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am done for today, so I created a github repo and push this code, this will be good for push me up to keep doing the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For the next days&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, this first day was nice, but I think didn&apos;t enjoy too much to write down all the things I made (what is a blog? :P), so I think for the next days I&apos;ll list the task after finish them but not too much in details unless I noticed something insteresting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hit me up!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please let me know if you read this some day, just a +1 could be great to my motivation :D (Yes, everything is about me)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>